字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Yeah that's nice!
这感觉真是太棒了！
Good to wash the fleas and lice out!
把这些虱子和跳蚤都洗掉！
Don't just sulk in the corner. Come over here.
嘿！别一个劲待在角落生闷气 到这里来
If you fall overboard, a sea serpent will eat you!
要是你掉下船 海蛇会把你吃掉！
-What? -He's ignoring us?
怎么？他这是在无视我们？
What a bore.
真是没意思
In the Middle Ages,
在中世纪
some of the Danes living in Denmark,
生活在丹麦的丹麦人中
the pirates who pillaged and plundered as an occupation,
有一些以海盗为生的人 到处劫掠抢夺
were called "Vikings."
他们被称为“维京人”
For these men,
那些人垂涎着
England held the abundant, wide-open lands that they yearned for.
英格兰人手里丰茂广阔的大片土地
In the beginning of the 9th century, Vikings invaded England,
九世纪初 维京人入侵了英格兰
and some settled north in England, which expanded their influence.
其中一些移居到了英格兰北部 以扩大自己的影响力
However, in 1002 A.D.,
不过 在公元1002年
the English Army attacked the Vikings settlers.
英格兰军队向这些维京移民开战
In response, the Danish Army sent ships to take revenge on England
为此 丹麦军队派船去英格兰复仇
and moved in for a direct attack.
直接就展开了攻击
By joining this political cause,
由于这些政治动机
the Vikings took it upon themselves to fight in a war of revenge
维京人自发地向英格兰军队
against the English Army.
发起了复仇之战
EPISODE 6: THE JOURNEY BEGINS
第六集：旅程的开始
Put your backs into!
别停下！
Move your arms!
我说了 你们手臂动起来！
Shut up!
闭嘴！
What do you think I'm doing!
我已经在划了！
Oh, dear. Whoever did this wasn't very tidy.
天哪 干这个的人可干得不太干净啊
All right. This spot looks good.
好吧 这里可以
Stop the boat!
停船！
CENTRAL ENGLAND, NEAR GAINSBOROUGH
（英格兰中部 根斯堡附近）
Man, it's hard to walk around here.
伙计 这里可不太好走路啊
And the stench is awful.
这臭味也太熏人了
Damn it.
该死的
These guys aren't normal soldiers, right?
这些人可不是普通士兵 是吧？
They were hired by the Danish Army like us.
他们是被丹麦军队雇佣来的 和我们一样
The Danish Army?
丹麦军队？
The Vikings have a hand in the war?
维京人也参与这场战争了？
They're starting skirmishes with the English Army here and there.
他们开始随意在各处 攻击一下英格兰军队
Vikings are spectacular tools of war.
一场宏伟的战争必然有维京人参与
At any rate, the Danish king plans to invade England.
这么发展下去 丹麦国王会计划入侵英格兰
Years could pass in the meantime, but this is the groundwork.
那可能还需要好几年才会发生 但这就是在为此做准备
So they're clearing out anyone who could get in the way.
所以他们是事先把碍事的先除掉？
Before the king arrives.
为国王到来做准备
That's right. And if we help out…
没错 如果我们能帮一把的话
the rewards will be bountiful.
回报会非常丰厚
So many insects here.
最近这里虫子非常多
It's better than sitting in the cold. Now is the time we make our fortune.
那也比受冻好
How about it? Not a bad deal.
怎么样？这笔交易不错吧
The feudal lord of this land has been burdened by the English Army.
这片土地上的封建领主 显然和英格兰军队处得不好
We're an army of over 100 men.
我们可是一支超一百人的军队
And frankly, we're superior to you in a fight.
坦白说 我们在战场上 比你们更胜一筹
That's a big mouth for a common pirate.
一个小小的海盗 口气倒挺大
There's no need for that.
没必要这么说吧
We're all Danes here.
大家都是丹麦人
Don't compare yourself to me.
可别把我们当成一类人
What's that supposed to mean?
你这话什么意思？
Come now. In a few years, there's gonna be an invasion, right?
拜托 再过几年 入侵就真的要到来了 对吧？
In which case, you better take a few preliminary measures.
这样的话 你应该先把准备工作做好
None of your soldiers would have to die.
那你的士兵就都能活着
What do you want in return?
那你要什么回报呢？
Seven pounds of gold.
2.7公斤黄金
The treasure and food of the lord of the land.
这个地方领主储藏的财富和食物 都归我们
And we take all the women.
所有女人也归我们
Five pounds. Then do as you wish.
2.3公斤黄金 其它的都随便你
Then it's settled! End of negotiation.
那就定了！谈判结束
What's that all about?
那是怎么回事？
We've been given a job.
我们有新工作了
All right! Better eat up then!
好了！那赶紧吃吧！
Tomorrow, we will send an official envoy.
我们明天就会派出正式使节
We'll leave the war plans to you, but don't go running off.
至于战争的计划 就交给你了 但你们可别跑了
You'll have nowhere to retreat.
你们就是撤退 也会无处可去
If you try to deceive--
如果你们想骗我们…
We're surrounded?
我们被包围了？
-You didn't hear them? -You're noisy!
嘿 大耳！
Shoot!
发射！
This is perfect for my digestion.
这正好让我消消食
I'll kill you!
我要杀了你！
Beat them at their own game!
就让我们在他们的战场上打败他们！
Shoot!
发射！
Damn it!
该死的！
Accomplish something on the battlefield.
去战场上立下一些战功
Once you do,
等你立下战功
I'll reward you with a duel.
我就奖励你一场决斗
Accomplish something.
立下战功…
Brat!
小子
You a pirate too?
你也是海盗吗？
If you must hate someone, hate the Danes.
如果你一定要恨谁 那就恨丹麦人吧
Excuse me. You still alive?
抱歉 你还活着？
The weak will die on the battlefield.
弱者会死在战场上
Like you.
比如你
Damn it.
该死的
Little punk!
该死的小子！
Die!
去死吧！
Get over here!
混蛋！
You're starting to look like a warrior.
你终于有点战士的样子了
Hey, Thorfinn.
嘿 托尔芬
Could you be our spy for a while?
你能给我们当一下间谍吗？
What? Why should I?
什么？我为什么要帮你们？
Boy! How dare you!
小子！你胆子真大啊！
Hold him down. I'll kill him!
压住他 我要杀了他！
There he is!
在这里！
Over there!
那里！
That way! Don't let him escape!
那条路！别让他跑了！
Don't you wish our king was a little less foolish?
我们现在这个国王有点傻 你说呢？
Mother! You can't say such things aloud!
母…母亲！你不能这么大声说！
Two generations ago, King Edgar was a good king.
两代之前的埃德加国王是个好国王
He got along with the Danes.
他和丹麦人处得很好
Everyone respected him.
所有人都很尊敬他
That king was a fine Christian.
那个国王是个好基督徒
But His Majesty King Ethelred will ruin us all.
但埃塞尔雷德陛下会毁掉我们所有人
He killed all the Danish settlers living in this country.
他忽然下令 把国内所有丹麦移民都杀掉
Of course they're angry.
丹麦人当然要生气了
Mother, you shouldn't say such things in front of others.
母亲 你不能在别人面前说这些
What if a soldier hears you?
如果被某个士兵听到怎么办？
Mother!
母亲！
Mother, wait!
母亲 等等！
YEAR 1008 A.D. EASTERN ENGLAND, EAST ANGLIA
（公元1008年 英格兰东部 东英吉利）
Oh, you're awake.
哦 你醒了
We were just about to have supper.
我们正准备吃晚饭呢
How is your injury?
你的伤怎么样了？
We've washed your clothes.
我们洗了你的衣服
Wear that for now.
现在就穿那个吧
Your dagger is there, too.
你的匕首也在那里
The clothes may fit a little big.
这些衣服对你来说可能有点大
But they're all the boy clothes we have.
但这是我们仅有的男孩的衣服
Now, have a seat. You must be hungry, right?
过来 坐下吧
He seems famished.
他看起来非常饿…
What is your name?
你叫什么名字？
Where did you come from?
你从哪里来？
What happened to your parents?
你父母在哪里？
See? He doesn't understand our language.
瞧见没？他听不懂我们的语言
-He might be Danish. -What are you saying?
他可能是丹麦人
No matter who he is, you can't just leave an injured child.
不管他是谁 我们都不能不管一个受伤的孩子
Jesus wouldn't forgive you.
你要是那么做 上帝是不会原谅你的
But the Danes are enemies of England, aren't they?
可丹麦人是英格兰的敌人 不是吗？
Father was conscripted because of the Danish invasion.
就是因为丹麦人的入侵 父亲才被应征入伍的
And what of it?
那又怎样？
There is no reason women and children should participate in the wars of men.
女人们和孩子们 不应该参与男人的战争
As true as that may be…
虽然话是这么说…
This child has fleas!
这孩子身上有跳蚤！
Stop scratching!
别挠！
They're getting in the food!
跳蚤都跳进食物里面去了！
See?
看到没？
Don't you feel better?
这样是不是感觉好一点了？
Goodness. Boys sure are so grubby.
天哪 男孩子们可真是邋遢
My youngest was always scratching too.
我最小的儿子也总是挠痒痒
So I would comb his hair every time.
所以我每一次都会给他梳头
Two years ago, he caught a disease and died.
他两年前得病死掉了
I don't understand the language you're speaking.
我听不懂你说的话…
But I'm not an Englishman.
但我不是英格兰人
What's this?
你说什么？
So your mouth does work!
所以你会说话咯！
Woman!
女人！
Yes? What is your business?
怎么？你有事吗？
A Danish spy is hiding in these parts. Have you seen any suspicious kids?
这附近藏着一个丹麦间谍
A kid?
一个孩子？
A pirate child?
一个海盗孩子？
Don't be fooled.
可别被骗了
He managed to kill two of His Excellency's men.
他很厉害 杀掉了我们总督大人手下两个人
There's a wound on his left arm.
他左臂被箭刺伤
Woman.
女人 那是你儿子吗？
Yes, that's right.
对 没错
My youngest son, John. Is there a problem?
我最小的儿子 约翰 有问题吗？
The child is just about his age.
那个孩子跟他差不多大
If you see him, report it!
如果看到他 要立即报告！
Do you realize what you're doing?
你知道你在做什么吗？
That boy is a pirate!
那个男孩是个海盗！
Despite being a child he's apparently killed two people!
他只是个孩子 可他已经杀了两个人了！
Why are you hiding him?
你为什么要把他藏起来？
It's not normal for a child to be a pirate.
一个孩子变成海盗是不正常的
There must be a reason for it.
他一定有他的原因
What reason? Whatever it is this isn't the time to find out.
如果有 那又会是什么呢？
That boy won't replace John.
这个男孩无法成为约翰的替代品
I'm going to the soldiers to…
我要去找士兵们去…
Run.
跑…
Run away.
离开这里
Wait a moment!
等等！
John!
约翰！
-Do you see Thorfinn's signal? -It should come soon.
你看到托尔芬的信号了吗？
I see it!
我看到了！
There it is!
在那里！
Fire!
着火了！
The shore hut is on fire!
岸边的棚子着火了！
Gather the men!
快把人召集起来！
Hurry!
快！
Bring buckets!
带上桶！
So it was you!
果然就是你！
So you disguised yourself!
你伪装了自己 小子！
What?
嘿…嘿…
What is that?
那是什么？
That's awful.
太可怕了…
Damn it!
该死的！
Who is this child?
那个孩子是谁？
Did he kill them?
是他杀了他们吗？
Why are you here? I told you to run!
你为什么到这里来？我让你跑的！
I said it properly in English!
我是用正儿八经的英语说的！
He's coming this way!
他朝这里过来了！
You can still make it! Escape to the forest!
你还有机会的！逃到树林里去！
Get far away from the sea! If you don't hurry, they'll--
离大海远一点！
Hey, what is that?
嘿 那是什么？
No!
不…
Run!
跑！
Forget the fire!
别管火了！
Everyone, run!
大家快跑！
Vikings!
是维京人！
Well done, Thorfinn.
嘿 干得不错 托尔芬
This village is livelier than I expected.
这个村子比我想象得更热闹
Don't waste time!
别磨蹭！
Clear this place out before the army arrives!
在敌军来之前 杀掉所有人！